# Jose Mari Ponce

### Full-stack Software Engineer

I'm a Software Engineer with more than 12 years of professional experience. I've been engaged in various web application architectures. My most recent technology stack is developing cloudnative applications using Vue.js, Node.js, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase and MySQL.



SKILLS

Vue.is

**Firebase** 

**EDUCATION** 

05/2000 - 04/2004

08/2019 - Present

Google Cloud

HackerRank

TestDome

Scrum Alliance

(05/2020)

(05/2020)Coursera

Coursera

CERTIFICATIONS

Node.js

**GSuite** 

major in Software Technology

Master of Information Systems

Associate Cloud Engineer (09/2020 - 09/2022)

Node.js Rest API (Intermediate) (08/2020)

Certified Scrum Master (02/2012 - 02/2014)

Cloud Architecture with Google Cloud Specialization

Cloud Engineering with Google Cloud Specialization

**CONFERENCES & COURSES** 

Vue.js (Hard) (11/2019 - 11/2022)

De La Salle University - Manila

ponce.josemari@gmail.com

+61 39 0881383

Melbourne, Australia

ecnop.dev 👄

**Philippines** 

**Philippines** 

linkedin.com/in/ecnopdev in

Google Cloud Platform

MySQL

**SCRUM** 

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

University of the Philippines - Open University

twitter.com/ecnopdev

github.com/ecnopdev 🔘

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineer Singapore Press Holdings

09/2014 - Present

Singapore

Design, develop and implement cloud-native enterprise applications. Achievements/Tasks

- Migrated 8 enterprise applications to various cloudnative architectures using Vue.is, Node.is, Firebase and Google Cloud Platform.
- Implemented a suite of mobile applications for journalists used for covering big events.
- Developed a company-wide migration tool for converting Lotus Notes documents to Google Doc.
- Lead 3 SCRUM teams and facilitated sprints using JIRA.

Contact: Norman Quek - Manager - quekch@sph.com.sg

# Software Engineer

Orica Australia 07/2013 - 08/2014

**Philippines** 

Global application support for business applications built on Lotus Notes and Xpages.

Achievements/Tasks

- Closed more than 80 application support tickets where I work remotely with users from all over the world.
- Completed several major enhancements for 4 legacy systems.

Contact: Prashant Bhaysar - Supervisor prashant.bhavsar@orica.com

## **Systems Analyst**

## Sun Life of Canada Philippines

12/2011 - 06/2013

**Philippines** 

Design, develop and implement business applications using Lotus Notes and Java

Achievements/Tasks

 Lead developer in implementing the policy contract system for Sun Life Vietnam

### Software Engineer Abbott Laboratories

08/2011 - 12/2011

**Philippines** 

**Philippines** 

Design, develop and implement business applications using Lotus Notes.

## Software Engineer Softweb Consulting Incorporated

**Table Tennis** 

**Mobile Games** 

Musical Intruments

#### **AWARDS**

Dean's Lister

De La Salle University - Manila

### INTERESTS

02/2008 - 07/2011

Notes

Achievements/Tasks Pioneer of Xpages and SCRUM

Contact: Glenn Liwanag - Supervisor - glennliwanag@gmail.com

Design, develop and implement business applications using Lotus